#### **CERTIFICATIONS**













# **SKILLS**

- · Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, AKS
- · Azure, AWS, Terraform
- CI/CD (Jenkins,GitLab,Github, argoCD, SonarQube, Nexus, ZAP)
- · AWS ECS, AWS Cloudformation
- GitOps (argoCD, flux)
- Observability Stack (Grafana, Prometheus, Coroot )
- MLOps (mlflow-seldon)
- · Maven, Gradle, Ant
- Web servers (httpd, Nginx, Traefik)
- · app servers (tomcat)
- Database-administration (PostgreSQL, MySQL, mongo DB)
- · Kafka, Elasticsearch
- Monitoring Tools Prometheus, Grafana, Kibana, Promtail, Loki, Azure monitor, EFK
- Linux administration, bash scripting, python-scripting( beginner)
- · OS Red hat, Ubuntu, Cent OS

# **VISWAJITH VENU**



### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

DevOps engineer certified in Kubernetes administration with 6+ years of experience in managing infrastructure for applications. Configuring CICD pipeline and production deployments. I love my job and look forward to learning about intelligent automation and technologies. Looking for DevOps Engineer role to explore more.



https://github.com/Viswajith96

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/viswajith-v-52524212a/

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Cloud Platform Engineer**

Exerp (July 2023 – Present) Location: Denmark (Remote)

Roles and Responsibilities till now:

- Configure, Upgrade, and maintain production (AWS EKS)
  Kubernetes clusters and related components for dev, stage, and production environments.
- · Work on the infrastructure requirements and maintenance using terraform.
- Build a centralized monitoring solution in AWS for collecting and Visualizing application logs and matrices using EFK stack.
- Configure CICD pipelines using Github actions and GitOps (ArgoCD).

# **Senior DevOps Engineer**

Sedai (June 2022 – July 2023) Location: Trivandrum

Roles and Responsibilities till now:

- Configured production (AWS EKS) Kubernetes clusters for multitenant micro service application Kubernetes deployment.
- Built a centralized logging solution in Azure for collecting and Visualizing application logs and matrices using open-source tools such as Grafana, Prometheus and Loki.

#### **EDUCATION**

PG: Cloud Computing from IIT

Palakkad

BTech: Electronics and

Communication Engineering(ECE)

CGPA: 8.43

### **PERSONAL CONTACT**

Email:

vishnukarthikayam@gmail.com

Mob:

+917012740117, +919567613278

- Installed and configured open-source observability tools based on eBPF Technology for fetching Latency metrics and more information about the application performance.
- Installed and configured Kubernetes runtime security monitoring and alerting using falco (an eBPF Based security tool for Kubernetes clusters.)
- Migrated CICD pipelines from AWS Code-pipeline to Github actions.
- · Prepare and Maintain terraform templates for various infrastructure requirements.
- · Implemented centralized metrics collection using Prometheusthanos.
- Configured AWS EKS K8s cluster backup using Velero and AWS S3 as backend.
- · Participated in various R&D Tasks related to a cloud cost optimisation product development.

# **HOBBIES**

· Cycling

Travelling

# **DevOps Engineer**

UST (March 2018 – June 2022)

Roles and Responsibilities:

 Configured production (Azure Kubernetes Service -AKS) and development infrastructure for monolithic and micro service applications for both conventional deployment and Kubernetes deployment.

Location: Trivandrum

- · Fostered a culture of continuous integration & continuous delivery which reduced deployment time in development environment from 30-40 minutes to 2 minutes.
- Worked together with product managers, Engineering head for procuring and managing azure subscription, plan, and configure new infrastructure requirements, SAAS solutions etc.
- Monitoring Production applications and help customers in solving live issues as soon as possible.
- · Administrator and control of Kubernetes including rolling updates, roll backs and disaster recovery.
- Configured and maintaining monitoring solutions such as ELK stack, PLG stack, Nagios etc.
- Configured CICD pipeline (GitLab CICD and using Jenkins as CICD tool) with Git-Ops (Argo CD) for Kubernetes deployment.

- · Configured and maintained MLOps pipeline for Data science team using mlflow and seldon.
- Prepare and maintain helm charts for Microservice deployments.
- · Configured AKS and Vanila K8s cluster backup using Velero.
- Configured Kubernetes security for the prod deployment using Trivy, kube-audit, apparmor and Falco.
- Load testing and performance tuning using apache JMeter and first level security testing using OWASP- ZAP and burp suite.
- Manage and Configure Email solutions based on Product requirement using MS Exchange online, Mail gun and Postfix mail server.
- Configure and maintain team's collaboration tools such as JIRA,
  Confluence, MS app center.
- Migrated existing pre-prod environment (dev, UAT, stage) from docker swarm to a self-managed high available Kubernetes cluster built using Kubeadm.

### **Trainee - Service Desk**

FLYTXT mobile solutions Pvt Ltd (July 2017 - March 2018)

Location: Trivandrum

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Distribute and assign the live issues to respective teams based on priority.
- · automate monitoring jobs using bash scripting.
- Monitor the status of production application instances and perform first level of troubleshooting.

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated here in above are true and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.